Kobato.
Dou sureba iin dakke?
Atarimae no kototte itsumo
Muzukashii na
Ureshii toki waratte
Suki na toki ni utaitai dake
Na no ni
Itsuka negai wa kanau to
Demo "itsuka" tte dore kurai?
Machikirenai yo
123! no aizu de ryoute hirogete
Zenshin ni hikari wo atsumete
Doko ni aru no?
Oshiete, watashi ni dekiru koto
Meippai kizu tsuite
Seiippai hashitte
Nan juu kai koronde naite
Sore de mo mada
Akireru kurai
Ashita wo shinjiteru
...Day to Say Goodbye.
Kobato.
What are you laughing in your sleep about?
Huh? Was I laughing?
With that smile, you looked like the
happiest person in the world.
Must have been a good dream.
Oh, yes!
A long time ago...
Huh?
Um...
It was a very happy dream.
It was a dream about the place
you wish to go to, wasn't it?
Huh?
Notice of Kindergarten Closure
We hereby give notice that this kindergarten is
no longer in operation. We truly apologize for
any inconveniences this may cause. Should you
wish to make an inquiry in relation to this
closure, please contact the principal, Sayaka Okiura.
Sayaka Okiura
Yomogi Kindergarten
Thank you
Goodbye, Yomogi Kindergarten
Good morning!
Good morning, Kobato.
What shall we tidy up today?
I'm off work now.
Yeah. See you.
Pretty hard work, isn't it?
There are so many of them.
I'm fine! I can still work hard!
You're right. In order to renew,
we need to get rid of the old.
Get rid of the old...
Let's take the ones that have
been bound out front.
Yes.
Let's have a tea break when
we're done with this.
Uh... Okay!
It's kind of tough without
Fujimoto's help, isn't it?
He's busy with work, isn't he?
Thank you very much.
You know, you don't have to push yourself
by taking on additional shifts.
No. Please put me in.
But you don't have to earn so
much anymore, do you?
If you're firing me, please say so.
No, you're not fired! That's not it at all!
You don't understand, do you?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for deciding to quit the kindergarten.
Huh?
But I need you to understand this.
Right now, I feel that it was the best decision.
I don't regret it.
I did it not because of what Okiura told me.
In the end it was my decision.
That's how I feel.
Yes.
What is it?
Um, would you please drop
by the kindergarten once?
Because, um... there are still things
there that belong to you and...
No.
Because, um... there are still things
there that belong to you and...
Feel free to throw it all away.
But...
I'm too busy to go.
For pedestrians and bicycles
Oh, Fujimoto here. I'm afraid I'm
going to be about an hour late.
Fujimoto?
Watch where you're going!
Huh?
I heard you were going to be late today.
I was finished earlier than I thought.
Get that long look off of your face.
You're even making me depressed.
I'm sorry.
What are you thinking about?
What do you want to do?
I'm not really sure, but...
But?
It hurts right here.
Yomogi Kindergarten closed down,
and it was a good thing for Ms. Sayaka.
But still...
Fujimoto, is it?
What? Fujimoto?
What kind of reaction is that?!
Aren't you aware of your feelings?
Oh, brother. I don't believe it.
Fujimoto?
Good morning.
Are you working today, too?
Yes I am.
But isn't today the day they're
taking the kindergarten down?
I've got to go.
He could have at least taken today off.
Well then.
The next-door neighbor has gone out.
I guess I'll be on my way too.
Are you going somewhere?
Yeah. I'll be back by night.
Now get that look off of your face.
Okay...
Come on.
You'd better hurry, too. You're going to be late.
Y-Yes sir!
Has the glass all been removed?
Keep going, keep going, keep going...
Yes!
Okay, stop!
Good work, guys.
Teacher, did you get your stuff out?
We took everything out yesterday.
So we can get to work now, can we?
Where's that guy with the evil glare?
He's gone to work.
Why, that's awfully cold.
I mean this place took good care of him.
He ought to show more respect.
He is not cold!
Fujimoto is a very busy person!
Uh... Hey, I'm sorry.
It's just that Mr. Okiura asked me to give
him a message. Thanking him and stuff.
Says he can't come by for a while.
Yes, he told me.
Huh?
I guess he had it in with the top.
Though we guys at the bottom of the
ladder really have no idea what goes on.
A-And how is Mr. Okiura?
No worries. He'll do fine.
After all, he is Mr. Okiura.
Ms. Sayaka!
Kobato.
Everyone?!
What's the matter?
Well, today's the day to say goodbye, so...
We came to see.
I told my mother that I was coming here.
Is that so? Thank you.
Is it all right to begin now, boss?
Teacher, can we start?
Please go ahead.
Okay now, let's move back so we don't get hurt.
Okay!
Okay, begin!
Bye-bye.
I'll say it again.
That is a request that I cannot help you with.
Give it up.
Hey!
Sir Genko, that's not fair.
You all having your snacks before me.
I'm having mine too!
Zuisho, be quiet.
Yes? Hm?
What?! You're going to catch Ushagi-san?!
That's right. We'll take Ushagi-san
hostage, and then persuade him.
Do you seriously think "God" is
going to agree to a deal like that.
It's better than not doing anything.
It's not such a light contract, including
the present situation we're in.
Ginsei is right. What he says is a lot
more practical than your ideas.
It's not about how heavy or light things are.
We can change that later, however we wish.
Give me a break! Didn't you learn
anything from what we went through?
Oh, the both of you!
So you're planning to use force again, are you?
Well, if you haven't figured out who it would hurt
the most, why don't I spell it out for you?!
Sorry.
Never mind.
Perhaps what "God" was trying to
teach you was about waiting.
Sure enough. That's one topic
I'm not very good at.
Hey!
I get the message. I won't do anything.
My name is Iorogi. I will be
with you from now on.
Teacher. When we're finished cleaning up,
entry will no longer be permitted.
Yes. Thank you.
Well then, teacher, you all take care now. Bye.
I thought we had a lot of space,
but looking at it now...
Right?
Kobato, I'd like to ask you a favor.
Do you mind?
Yes?
I'd like you to help Fujimoto.
What?
Yomogi Kindergarten may very
well have tied him down.
I really think so.
Tied him down... to what?
I was counting on him to continue being
the hard working Fujimoto as always.
I kept relying on him.
I should have noticed much sooner for his sake.
You're a great help, Fujimoto.
Teacher Fujimoto!
Play the organ for us!
I should have told him to do what
he wanted to do, for himself.
But no! Fujimoto was truly
just doing his best to...
Yes. All the more reason why I should have.
Because he's the type of person
who goes out of his way.
So, Kobato, please do that for me.
Stay by his side.
But Ms. Sayaka you...
That's not my job.
Not anymore.
Kobato!
Oh, hello. I'm back.
Something terrible has happened!
Domoto, why did you?
As promised, I didn't contact any of
Yomogi Kindergarten's personnel.
But I did tell the landlady.
Tch!
Sorry Kobato.
He didn't want to worry you.
It's his way of being nice...
Um, your arm.
I-I'm glad you weren't hurt too badly.
Please don't push yourself.
Everyone will worry.
It will be inconvenient not
being able to use one hand.
Please let me know if there's
anything I can do for you.
I did tell you that day we first met at
Yomogi Kindergarten, didn't I?
Huh?
That if it's out of sympathy
or curiosity, don't bother.
If you're feeling sorry for me,
I want you to stop it.
It's not like that!
You're a nuisance!
No... Fujimo...
No...
Is this for me?
Huh?
He says you're to collect the
kompeito by the next full moon.
Otherwise, your destination will be
determined according to the contract.
Hey, Ushagi-san.
How does one get an extension on that?!
So what's going to happen from now?
What do you think we should do?
I don't know. It's up to him.
One thing's for sure. He must
be feeling responsible.
If it weren't for that battle,
she wouldn't have...
...she wouldn't have been sucked into this,
and that wouldn't have happened.
If there's anything I can do, I'll do it.
So please, give us until
another four seasons pass.
No... Just one will do!
I'm begging you!
You're saying "no"?!
Hey!
Nakushita mono to
Atsumeta mono no hazama ni
Anata no egao ochiteita no
Todokisou de todokanai
Tonde yukeru wake janai shi
Warawasete agetai dake na no ni,
Yaku tatazu no kono tsubasa
Nan no tame ni aru no darou?
Anata no soba de warau yo,
Watashi ni dekiru koto
Atatameru dake de mo ii no kana
Semete tsutsumitai
Kizuku no, sono tame no tsubasa to
Ima koso watashi warau yo
Next episode
...Kobato's Wish.
Ima koso watashi warau yo
Next episode
...Kobato's Wish.